嘿，你们好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series
那么上次我们提到这可能是个好主意，当Hazel还处于早期开发阶段
so last time we mentioned that it's probably a good idea, while Hazel is still kind of early on in development
讨论预编译头文件，并实际开始使用预编译头文件
to actually talk about precompiled headers, and actually start using precompiled headers
所以那就是我们今天要做的，如果你们还没看过上期视频，一定要去那儿看
so that's what we're going to do today, if you can't watch the previous episode, definitely watch it there
那就是我们在之前的视频中所计划的事件系统
that's what we actually set up that event system that we planned in the episode before that
但今天我们要讲的是上周讲的预编译头文件
but yeah today's gonna be all about precompiled headers now I did last week
制作的一个关于C++系列中预编译头文件的视频，所以一定要去看看
just make a video about precompiled headers in the C++ series, so check that out
我这么做的原因显然是，预编译头文件不仅仅适用于我们正在构建的游戏引擎
the reason I did that is because obviously precompiled headers are more than just applicable through this game engine that we're building
并且我还想做一个更通用的视频，那只是关于它们的原理，以及我们为什么要使用它们
and I wanted to make a more generic the video, that's just about how they work and why we want to use them
所以如果你们不确定预编译头文件是什么，一定要看看那个视频
so definitely check out that video, if you're not sure what a precompiled header is
因为我不会在这儿花太多时间解释它，那大概是一个20多分钟的关于预编译头文件的视频
because I'm not gonna spend too much time explaining it here, that's like a 20 plus minute video about precompiled headers
不管怎样，所以在这个视频中我们不会讨论它们是什么，只会直接实现它们
anyway, so instead of really talking about what they are in this video, we're just gonna go ahead and implement them
所以如果你们还不知道的话，请先看那个视频
so yeah watch that video first, if you haven't already
然后我们跳到实现预编译头文件
and then let's just jump into implementing precompiled headers
那么看看这里所有的Hazel/src，显然有一堆东西是我们最后要用到的
so looking at all of our Hazel/src here, there's obviously a bunch of stuff that we're going to end up using
这需要使用很多标准库的东西，比如，我们在这里提前包含了memory
that requires the use of many kind of standard library things, like for example we're including memory here in advance
你们知道的，包含string，包含functional，所有这些
you know, including string, we're including functional
所有这些东西都可以在字符串流中，所有这些东西都可以移到一个预编译头文件中
all the thing all of these things can be in a string stream, all these things can be moved into a precompiled header
并且当然，这个Hazel项目目前还很年轻
and of course this Hazel project is quite young at the moment
我们只使用了其他数据结构，比如向量
we'd only been using like other data structures, like vector for example
所以现在创建那个预编译头文件是一个很好的主意
um so it's a really good idea to actually create that precompiled header now
因为我们没有太多的源文件，这意味着我们实际上不需要花太多的时间来编辑这些
because we don't have too many source files, which means we don't need to spend too much time actually editing things
这很好，好了，那么我们要做的第一件事是在src下
which is quite nice, ok, so the first thing we're going to do is under src
实际上，我要创建一个新文件，创建一个头文件和cpp文件
I'm actually going to make a new file, which I'm gonna make a header file and a cpp file
我把它叫做hzpch，所以是hzpch.h，然后还需要创建一个c++文件hzpch.cpp
and I'm gonna call it hzpch, so hzpch.h add, and then also we need to make a C++ file called hzpch.cpp
这将包含我们的hzpch.h文件，这是VS所需要的
this will include our hzpch.h file, this is needed for visual studio
因为VS预编译头文件需要一个包含预编译头文件的源文件
because visual studio precompiled headers require a source file, which includes the precompiled header
而其他的编译器，如gcc或clang就不需要，而在这里，这将是一个预编译头
whereas other compilers like clang or gcc do not, and then over here, this is gonna be a precompiled header
那么我想做的第一件事是如果我们在Windows中
so the first thing I want to do is if we're actually in Windows
所以如果HZ_PLATFORM_WINDOWS存在的话，我将包含Windows.h
so if HZ_PLATFORM_WINDOWS, I'm actually going to include Windows.h
因为这肯定是需要的，而那正是我们想要的
because that's definitely going to be needed, and that's just something that we want to have available to us
如果Windows被定义了，这是属于预编译头文件的东西
if we're kind of, if Windows is actually defined, this is something that does belong in a precompiled header
但显然不是针对所有平台，我们可以为每个平台单独创建一个预编译头文件
however obviously not for all platforms, we could make, we could make a precompiled header be separate for each platform
不打算费这个劲，我不认为这是百分百必要的
I'm not gonna bother with that, I don't think that's 100% necessary
但也许特定于windows或其他特定于平台的头文件可以通过这种ifdef包含在这个pch中
but maybe Window specific or other platform specific headers can actually be included in this pch with this kind of ifdef
然后在这里，我们会放一些通用的东西，你们知道的，比如iostream，memory之类的
and then over here, we'll put common stuff, so stuff like iostream, stuff like memory, you know
utility，algorithm，我不会放太多东西，这里是functional
utility, algorithm, I'm not gonna put too much stuff, here functional what else did we have
然后你们知道的，还有数据结构，比如string，vector，unordered_map，unordered_set
and then you know, data structures like string vector, probably unordered_map, unordered_set
我不想在这里浪费太多时间，我们会在需要的时候添加一些东西
I don't want to waste too much time here, we'll kind of add stuff to this as we need them of course
但这可能是一个很好的集合，我想我们也用了sstream
but this is probably a good set, I think we also used sstream as well
像这样和string放在一起可能更有意义一些
probably makes more sense for this to be with string like this
但不管怎样，那大概是一个关于我们真正需要什么的好主意
but anyway, that's probably a Chad generally a good idea of what we actually need
如果我们看一下这个，它是一个string和functional，我也会从这里开始移除它们
if we go through this, it's a string functional, I'll start removing them as well from here
因为我们不需要它们，以及sstream，我们可以只在头文件本身中包含预编译头文件
because we don't need them, sstream, sstream, we can just include the precompiled header in header files themselves
顺便说一下，不只是在cpp文件里，过一遍，酷，酷，酷，这儿还有memory
by the way, doesn't just need to be in a cpp file, going through this, cool cool cool cool cool, memory we have
是的，就是那样，酷，好吧，那是我们的预编译头，它有我们需要的一切
yeah that's about it, cool, okay, so there's our precompiled header, it's got everything we need now
现在让我们把它添加到premake，所以在Hazel中，我要打开那个premake文件
now let's go ahead and add it to premake, so in Hazel, I'm going to just kind of open that premake file
我们要讨论的是，我们需要添加到项目中的所有内容
yeah yeah we're gonna talk about, all we actually need to add to our projects
或者是Hazel项目来使用pch
or specifically the Hazel project to actually use pch
那么我们首先要指定的是pch头文件
so the first thing we need to specify is which header file is our pch
所以我们要写pchheader，然后是头文件的名字，像那样的hzpch.h
so we're gonna write pchheader and then the name of the header file, which is a hzpch.h like that
那就意味着使用hzpch.h文件，对吧，然后是为了VS
that means use the hzpch.h file, right, and then for visual studio
因为它也需要创建一个pch文件，实际上，我们需要输入pchsource
because it actually needs to create a pch file as well, we need to actually type pchsource
在我们不需要这个的平台上，这个可以被移除
now this can be excluded on platforms in which we don't need this
或者更确切地说，对于我们生成的项目的编译器我们实际上不需要这个
or rather for compilers for projects that we generate well, we actually don't need this
但对于VS，我们需要
but for visual studio, we do um
所以比如你们知道的，我们不需要把它放在system:windows过滤器下
so we don't have to put this under like you know filter system:windows or anything
在其他平台上它就会被忽略，酷
it will just be ignored on other kind of platforms, cool
那么然后在这儿，我们需要指定完整的路径，那么就是Hazel/src/hzpch.cpp
so and then here, we actually need to specify the full path, so Hazel src and then hzpch.cpp
好了，那就相当于我们直接去
okay, so that is kind of the equivalent of us going ahead
然后说，你们知道的，在VS中，请创建我的预编译头文件
and saying you know, behind visual studio, please create my precompiled header file
然后这就相当于进入我们的项目，并且就像
and then this is the equivalent of kind of just going into our project, and being like
嘿，我要用pch，它将是hzpch.h，好了，所以那就是所有的内容
hey you know, I'm going to use pch and it's going to be hzpch.h, okay, so that's what that is all about
这里不要保存，好了，酷，所以那就是我们要写的
and let's not save our changes here, okay, cool, so that's all we need to write again
我刚刚为Hazel做了这个，如果你们最终有大量的Sandbox应用
I've just done this for Hazel, if you kind of end up with substantial Sandbox application
你们也可以在Sandbox中这样做，但现在，那就是我们所需要的
you can do that for Sandbox as well, but for now, that's all we need
那么让我们重新运行GenerateProjects文件，好了，一切都成功完成了
so let's rerun our GenerateProjects file, there we go, it's done everything successfully
如果我现在重新加载，我们应该可以右击这里，看到这里被标记为create
if I reload everything now, we should be able to right click here, and see that this is now marked as create
并且在我们的项目设置中，这不是常用的，hzpch.h是要使用的预编译头文件
and that in our kind of project settings, this is not as used, and hzpch.h is the precompiled header to use
酷，那么现在让我们清理构建一次，当然我们会得到一些错误
cool, so now let's do a clean build of everything, and of course we get several errors
因为我们需要确保hzpch.h文件是第一个被包含的文件
because we need to make sure that that hzpch.h file is the first thing
它被包含在每个cpp文件中，所以在最上面，我将包含hzpch.h
that's included in every single cpp file, so at the very top, I'm going to include hzpch.h
好了，并且每个文件都要这样做
okay, and this will be done for every single file
现在我认为src实际上在我们的编译器包含路径中，是的，这应该会让它变得简单
now I think src is actually in our in our compiler include paths, yes, it is that should make it easy
只需要包含那个，就那样，那么看看Application和Log.cpp
just need to include that, and that's it, so Application and then Log.cpp
每一个cpp文件都要看看，虽然我们只有两个
every single cpp file, we've only got like two though
所以那就是为什么我想在这个项目开始发展之前尽快完成它
so that's that's why I wanted to get this done as quickly as possible before this project starts growing a lot
所以如果我们再构建一次，你们可以看到我们没有得到错误，构建成功
so if we build this again, you can see that we get no errors it, built successfully
并且它花了5秒半，顺便说一下，作为一个例子，那是一个带有预编译头文件的清理构建
and it took five and a half seconds, by the way, as an example, that that's a clean build with precompiled headers
或者只是为了好玩，让我们来试试清理构建，看看Hazel需要多长时间来构建
or otherwise just do a clean build for fun, and see how long Hazel takes to build
所以使用预编译头文件，一个清理构建需要6秒，好了，而没有预编译头文件呢
so with precompiled headers, a clean build takes six seconds, okay, and without precompiled headers
那么我把预编译头设置为不使用，然后右键单击清理，右键单击构建
so I'll just set precompiled headers to not using, and then I'll right-click clean, right-click build
你们可以看到，花了7.6秒，所以稍微长一点，也不是很长
you can see, take seven point six second, so a little bit longer, not that much longer
然而，大多数构建时间的提升都来自于对单个源文件的编辑
however most the kind of build time improvements are gonna come from just editing individual source files
所以如果只是，我不知道，可以添加一个空格或其他东西，然后再次点击构建
so if I just kind of, I don't know, I could just add a space or something, and then hit build again
你们可以看到，就这个Application.cpp文件需要三秒钟才能重新编译
this one Application.cpp file, you can see, that it took three seconds to recompile
让我们再构建一次，只是为了有一个更好的更可靠的计时，大约是3.3秒
let's just do that again, just to have a better kind of more reliable timing, it's about three, three point three seconds
然后我会切换到使用预编译头文件，我会用这个新东西来构建所有东西
and then I will switch this to use precompiled headers, I'll just build everything with this new kind of thing
完成后，我去除了空格，点击构建，你们可以看到，它快了很多
and then once that is done, I'll have my space back, hit build, and you can see, it's quite a bit faster
然后如果我移走了空格，重新开始构建，好了，速度一直在加快
and then if I remove my space, and do my build again, there we go, so consistently faster
现在我们有了预编译头文件，随着项目规模的增长，它只会变得越来越快
now that we have precompiled headers, and that will only kind of get faster and faster as our project grows in size
好了，所以就是那样，你们可以看到，集成预编译头文件是多么容易
okay, so that's it, you can see, how easy it is to actually integrate precompiled headers
这真的一点也不烦人，因为不需要遍历我们拥有的100个cpp文件然后把它添加进去，对吧
it's really not annoying at all, because we didn't have to go through the 100 cpp files we had and then add it in, right
如果我们在这个系列后面做这个，会是什么情况呢
which would have been the case, if we had done this later on in the series
所以我很高兴我们能尽快解决这个问题
so I'm really happy to get us out of the way as quickly as possible really
这应该是任何大型项目的初始项目设置的一部分
this should be part of your initial project set up for any kind of large project
如果你们决定使用预编译头文件，那么好了，我们现在有了
if you've decided to use precompiled headers, so there we go, we have that now
并且你们可以看到，做这种事情有多容易，只需要pchheader
and you can see, how how easy it is to actually do this kind of stuff and pretty much, just pchheader
它是什么，我忘了它叫什么了，pchsource和pchheader
and what was it, actually I just forgot what it's called, yeah pchheader in pchsource
这就是你们所需要的，还有pchsource
and that's all you need, and the pchsource again
只有当你们使用MSVC作为编译器时，它才需要，好了
and then it only needed, if you're using MSVC as your compiler, okay
希望你们喜欢这个视频，如果喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
hope you guys enjoy this video, if you do, you know the like button
你们也可以通过访问patreon.com/thecherno来支持这个系列
you can also help support this series but got a patreon.com/thecherno
像往常一样，非常感谢所有让这个系列成为可能的赞助人
huge thank you, as always, to all the patrons that make this series possible
下一期已经为你们准备好了，而且你们可以访问的开发仓库已经有了所有这些东西
next episode is already up for you guys, and also the development repository that you get access to already has all this stuff
显然那就是我在视频之前实现的所有东西
obviously written that's where I implement everything way ahead of the videos
所以如果你们对此感兴趣的话，肯定有助于支持这个系列，去看看吧
so if you're interested in that, definitely helps support the series, and check that out
下次再见，我想我们终于可以开始讨论窗口了
I will see you guys next time, I think we're gonna finally be able to start talking about windows
就像图层和应用一样
and like layers and application kind of how that
它们是如何相互交织的应用程序运行循环等等
in how that intertwines and just application run loop and all that stuff
我想那将是我们接下来关注的内容，所以我们终于说到重点了
I think that's going to be the stuff that we focus on next, so finally we're getting to the point
我们可能在屏幕上有一个窗口，那将是令人兴奋的
where we might be able to have a window on something on the screen, that's gonna be exciting
那期视频再见，拜
I'll see you guys in that video, goodbye